A Warrior. A Leader. A Legend.
Geronimo: An American Legend is a western, history,
action film directed by Walter Hill.
The Apache Indians have reluctantly agreed to settle on
a US Government approved reservation.
Not all the Apaches are able to adapt to the life of corn farmers.
One in particular, Geronimo, is restless.
Pushed over the edge by broken promises and necessary actions by the government, Geronimo and thirty or so other warriors form
an attack team which humiliates the government by evading capture, while reclaiming what is rightfully theirs.
Lt. Charles Gatewood, played by Jason Patric.
Brig. Gen. George Crook, played by Gene Hackman.
Chief of Scouts Al Sieber, played by Robert Duvall.
Geronimo, played by Wes Studi.
2nd Lt. Britton Davis, played by Matt Damon.
Mangas, played by Rodney A. Grant.
Geronimo: An American Legend is a 1993 historical Western film starring Wes Studi, Jason
Patric, Gene Hackman, Robert Duvall, and Matt Damon in an early role.
The film, which was directed by Walter Hill, is
based on a screenplay by John Milius.
It is a fictionalized account of the Apache Wars
and how First Lieutenant Charles B.
Gatewood convinced Apache leader Geronimo to surrender in 1886.
The film explores themes of apache nation, native
american, historical figure, historical, cavalry.
The tone is emotional.